I'm assuming everyone here has watched
أفترض أن كل شخص هنا قد شاهد
a TED Talk online at one time or another, right?
محاضرة أو أكثر ل(تيد) على الإنترنت، أليس كذلك؟
So what I'm going to do is play this.
لذلك سوف أقوم بتشغيل هذه
This is the song from the TED Talks online.
هذه أغنية من محاضرات (تيد) على الإنترنت.
(Music)
(موسيقى)
And I'm going to slow it down
سأقوم بإبطائها.
because things sound cooler when they're slower.
لأن الأمور تبدو أفضل حين تكون أبطأ.
(Music)
(موسيقى)
Ken Robinson: Good morning. How are you?
كين روبينسون: صباح الخير، كيف حالكم؟
Mark Applebaum: I'm going to -- Kate Stone: -- mix some music.
مارك ابليبيوم: أنا بصدد ---- كاتي ستون: مزج بعض الموسيقى.
MA: I'm going to do so in a way that tells a story.
مارك ابليبيوم: سوف أقوم بذلك بطريقة حكاية قصة.
Tod Machover: Something nobody's ever heard before.
تود ماكوفر: شيء لم يسمعه أحد من قبل.
KS: I have a crossfader.
كاتي ستون: لدَي أداة دمج.
Julian Treasure: I call this the mixer.
جوليان تريشر: أدعو هذه خلاط.
KS: Two D.J. decks.
كاتي ستون: اسطوانتَي دي جى.
Chris Anderson: You turn up the dials, the wheel starts to turn.
كريس أندرسون: تدير القرص، تبدأ العجلة في الدوران.
Dan Ellsey: I have always loved music.
دان إلسي: لطالما أحببت الموسيقى.
Michael Tilson Thomas: Is it a melody or a rhythm or a mood or an attitude?
مايكل تيلسون توماس: ألحن هو أم إيقاع أم مزاج أم سلوك؟
Daniel Wolpert: Feeling everything that's going on inside my body.
دانيال ولبيرت: أشعر بكل ما يحدث داخل جسدي.
Adam Ockelford: In your brain is this amazing musical computer.
آدام أوكلفورد: يقبع في عقلك كمبيوتر موسيقي مذهل.
MTT: Using computers and synthesizers to create works. It's a language that's still evolving.
مايكل تيلسون توماس: باستعمال الحواسيب وأجهزة المزج لإنشاء أعمال. إنها لغة تتطور.
And the 21st century.
والقرن الحادي والعشرون.
KR: Turn on the radio. Pop into the discotheque.
كاتي ستون: شغل الراديو. موسيقى البوب داخل المرقص.
You will know what this person is doing: moving to the music.
ستعلمون ما يقوم به هذا الشخص: يتحرك على إيقاع الموسيقى.
Mark Ronson: This is my favorite part.
مارك رونسون: هذا مقطعي المفضل.
MA: You gotta have doorstops. That's important.
مارك ابليبيوم: يجب أن يكون لديك صدادات أبواب، ذلك مهم.
TM: We all love music a great deal.
تود ماكوفر: جميعنا نعشق الموسيقى.
MTT: Anthems, dance crazes, ballads and marches.
مايكل ت. توماس: الأناشيد وجنون الرقص والأغاني الشعبية والمسيرات.
Kirby Ferguson and JT: The remix: It is new music created from old music.
كيربي فيرجوسون و جى تي: الريمكس هو موسيقى جديدة تم إنشائها من موسيقى قديمة.
Ryan Holladay: Blend seamlessly.
ريان هولاداي: ممزوجة بشكل منسجم.
Kathryn Schulz: And that's how it goes.
كاثرين سكولز: وكذلك تسير الأمور.
MTT: What happens when the music stops?
مايكل تيلسون توماس: ماذا يحدث حين تتوقف الموسيقى؟
KS: Yay!
كاثرين سكولز: ياي!
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
MR: Obviously, I've been watching a lot of TED Talks.
مارك رونسون: من الواضح، أني كنت أشاهد الكثير من محاضرات (تيد).
When I was first asked to speak at TED,
حين تم طلبي أول مرة للحديث في (تيد)،
I wasn't quite sure what my angle was, at first,
لم أكن أعلم تمامًا ماهية محور حديثي، في البداية،
so yeah, I immediately started watching tons of TED Talks,
لذك، نعم، بدأت فورًا مشاهدة أطنان من محاضرات (تيد)،
which is pretty much absolutely
هذا من أكثر الأمور التي يمكنك القيام بها
the worst thing that you can do
سوءاً على الإطلاق
because you start to go into panic mode, thinking,
لأن الذعر والتفكير يبدئان في السيطرة عليك،
I haven't mounted a successful expedition to the North Pole yet.
لم أقم برحلة ناجحة للقطب الشمالي.
Neither have I provided electricity
ولم أقم بتوفير الكهرباء
to my village through sheer ingenuity.
لقريتي من خلال براعة فائقة.
In fact, I've pretty much wasted most of my life
في الواقع، أهدرت معظم حياتي
DJing in night clubs
كفتى دي جى بالنوادي الليلية
and producing pop records.
وعمل تسجيلات موسيقى البوب.
But I still kept watching the videos,
لكني لازلت مداوماً على مشاهدة الفيديوهات،
because I'm a masochist,
لأني مهووس،
and eventually, things like Michael Tilson Thomas
وفي نهاية المطاف، أشياء مثل رؤية مايكل تيلسون توماس
and Tod Machover, and seeing
وتود ماكوفر،
their visceral passion talking about music,
يتحدثون عن شغفهم العميق بالموسيقى،
it definitely stirred something in me,
بالطبع أثار شيئًا داخلي،
and I'm a sucker for anyone talking devotedly
وأنا شغوف لأي شخص يتحدث باخلاص
about the power of music.
عن قوة الموسيقى.
And I started to write down on these little note cards
وبدأت أدون على كروت الملاحظات الصغيرة تلك
every time I heard something
كل مرة أسمع شيئًا
that struck a chord in me, pardon the pun,
يضرب وتراً حساساً لدَي، عفوًا للتلاعب بالكلمات،
or something that I thought I could use,
أو شيئًا ما اعتقدت أنّ بامكاني استخدامه،
and pretty soon, my studio looked like this,
وبعد فترة وجيزة، أصبح الاستوديو الخاص بي يبدو مثل،
kind of like a John Nash, "Beautiful Mind" vibe.
شيء أشبه بجون ناش في فيلم "بيوتيفل مايند".
The other good thing about watching TED Talks,
الشيء الآخر الجيد في مشاهدة محاضرات تيد،
when you see a really good one,
حين تشاهد واحدة جيدة فعلًا،
you kind of all of a sudden wish the speaker
تتمنى فجأة لو أن المتحدث
was your best friend, don't you? Like, just for a day.
كان صديقك المقرب، أليس كذلك؟ ولو ليوم واحد على الأقل.
They seem like a nice person.
يبدو شخصًا رائعًا.
You'd take a bike ride, maybe share an ice cream.
ربما تقوما بجولة على الدراجة، أو ربما تتشاركا البوظة.
You'd certainly learn a lot.
بالتأكيد كنت ستتعلم الكثير.
And every now and then they'd chide you,
و بين الحين والآخر قد يعنفوك،
when they got frustrated that you couldn't really
حين يحبطون لأنك لا يمكنك حقًا
keep up with half of the technical things they're banging on about all the time.
مواكبة نصف الأشياء التقنية التي ينبهون لها كل وقت.
But then they'd remember that you're but a mere human
ثم يتذكرون أنك مجرد إنسان عادي
of ordinary, mortal intelligence
محدود الذكاء
that didn't finish university,
لم يكمل الجامعة،
and they'd kind of forgive you,
ويعفون عنك،
and pet you like the dog.
ويداعبوك مثل الكلب
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Man, yeah, back to the real world,
نعم، أعود إلى العالم الواقعي،
probably Sir Ken Robinson and I
تقريبًا سير كين روبنسون وأنا
are not going to end up being best of friends.
لن ينتهي بنا الأمر إلى أن نكون من أفضل الأصدقاء.
He lives all the way in L.A. and I imagine is quite busy,
هو يعيش بكل الطرق في لوس أنجلوس وأتصوره مشغولًا جدًا،
but through the tools available to me -- technology
لكن من خلال الأدوات المتاحة لي -- التكنولوجيا
and the innate way that I approach making music --
و الطريقة الغريزية التي انتهجها لصناعة الموسيقى --
I can sort of bully our existences
يمكنني نوعاً ما القيام بتنظيم وجودنا
into a shared event,
في حدث مشترك،
which is sort of what you saw.
مثل النوع الذي رأيتموه.
I can hear something that I love in a piece of media
يمكنني الاستماع لشيء ما أحبه في جزء من الإعلام
and I can co-opt it
وأدمجه
and insert myself in that narrative,
وأدخل نفسي في تلك الحكاية،
or alter it, even.
أو حتى أغيرها.
In a nutshell, that's what I was trying to do
باختصار، هذا ما كنت أحاول فعله
with these things, but more importantly,
بتلك الأشياء، لكن الأهم من ذلك،
that's what the past 30 years of music has been.
هو ما كانت عليه الموسيقى في الثلاثين سنة الماضية.
That's the major thread.
هذا هو الموضوع الرئيسي.
See, 30 years ago, you had the first digital samplers,
انظروا، منذ ثلاثون عامًا، كان لديكم أول دامجون رقميون،
and they changed everything overnight.
وغيروا كل شيء بين عشية وضحاها.
All of a sudden, artists could sample
فجأة، يمكن للفنانين أخذ أجزاء
from anything and everything that came before them,
من أي شيء وكل شيء جاء قبلهم،
from a snare drum from the Funky Meters,
من طبلة فريق فَنكي ميتر،
to a Ron Carter bassline,
إلى آلة رون كارتر الأساسية،
the theme to "The Price Is Right."
الموضوع ل"السعر مناسب."
Albums like De La Soul's "3 Feet High and Rising"
ألبومات مثل ألبوم
and the Beastie Boys' "Paul's Boutique"
"3 أقدام ويرتفع"
looted from decades of recorded music
"بوتيك بول"
to create these sonic, layered masterpieces
سابقة من الموسيقى المسجلة
that were basically the Sgt. Peppers of their day.
التي كانت أساسًا الرقيب فلفل من عصرهم.
And they weren't sampling these records
وكانوا لا يعيدون دمج تلك التسجيلات
because they were too lazy to write their own music.
لأنهم كانوا كسولين جدًا عن كتابة موسيقاهم الخاصة.
They weren't sampling these records to cash in on
كانوا لا يعيدون الدمج ليستفيدوا
the familiarity of the original stuff.
من الألفة مع أعمالهم الأساسية.
To be honest, it was all about sampling
لأكون صادقًا، كان كل شيء
really obscure things,
حول إعادة الدمج غامض حقًا،
except for a few obvious exceptions
ما عدا قليل من الاستثناءات
like Vanilla Ice and "doo doo doo da da doo doo"
الواضحة مثل فانيلا ايس و "دو دو دو دا دا دو دو"
that we know about.
التي نعلم عنها.
But the thing is,
لكن الأمر هو، إنهم كانوا
they were sampling those records
يعيدون دمج تلك التسجيلات
because they heard something in that music
لأنهم سمعوا شيئًا ما في تلك الموسيقى
that spoke to them
تتحدث إليهم
that they instantly wanted to inject themselves
أنهم يريدون حقن أنفسهم فورًا
into the narrative of that music.
داخل حكاية في تلك الموسيقى.
They heard it, they wanted to be a part of it,
سمعوها، وأرادوا أن يكونوا جزء منها،
and all of a sudden they found themselves
وفجأة وجدوا أنفسهم
in possession of the technology to do so,
وبحوزتهم تكنولوجيا تمكنهم من فعل ذلك،
not much unlike the way the Delta blues
ليس كثيرًا على عكس طريقة البلوز دلتا
struck a chord with the Stones and the Beatles and Clapton,
ضربوا الوتر مع الستونز والبيتلز وكلابتون،
and they felt the need to co-opt that music
وشعروا بالحاجة لدمج تلك الموسيقى
for the tools of their day.
في آلات عصرهم.
You know, in music we take something that we love
أتعرفون، في الموسيقى نأخذ شيئًا ما نحبه
and we build on it.
ونبني فوقه.
I'd like to play a song for you.
أود تشغيل أغنية لكم.
(Music: "La Di Da Di" by Doug E. Fresh &amp; Slick Rick)
(موسيقى: "لا دي دا دي" لدوج فريش وسليك ريك)
That's "La Di Da Di" and it's the fifth-most sampled
هذه "لا دي دا دي" وهى الخامسة من بين أكثر الأغنيات
song of all time.
المعاد إدماجها عبر التاريخ.
It's been sampled 547 times.
قد تم إعادة إدماجها 547 مرة.
It was made in 1984 by these two legends of hip-hop,
قام بعملها أسطورتي الهيب هوب
Slick Rick and Doug E. Fresh,
سليك ريك ودوج فريش في 1984،
and the Ray-Ban and Jheri curl look is so strong.
نظارة الراي بان وتسريحة شعر جيري تبدوان قويتان جدًا.
I do hope that comes back soon.
أتمنى عودة ذلك قريبًا.
Anyway, this predated the sampling era.
على أي حال، هذه سبقت عصر إعادة الدمج.
There were no samples in this record,
لم تكن هناك
although I did look up on the Internet last night,
أجزاء مدمجة في هذا التسجيل،
I mean several months ago,
الليلة الماضية، أعني منذ عدة شهور،
that "La Di Da Di" means, it's an old
تعني تلك ال"لا دي دا دي"، إنه تعبير كوكني قديم
Cockney expression from the late 1800s in England,
من أواخر القرن الثامن عشر في إنجلترا،
so maybe a remix with Mrs. Patmore
لذلك ربما يأتي قريبا ريمكس للسيدة باتمور
from "Downton Abbey" coming soon,
من "دير داوتون"
or that's for another day.
أو ذلك ليوم آخر.
Doug E. Fresh was the human beat box.
دوج إي فري كان طبلة بشرية.
Slick Rick is the voice you hear on the record,
سليك ريك هو الصوت المسموع في التسجيل،
and because of Slick Rick's sing-songy,
ولأن غناء سليك ريك رخيم، وفائق الجاذبية،
super-catchy vocals, it provides endless sound bites
يوفر مقطوعات وأجزاء لانهائية
and samples for future pop records.
لمستقبل تسجيلات موسيقى البوب.
That was 1984.
ذلك كان 1984.
This is me in 1984, in case you were wondering
هذا أنا عام 1984، في حالة إن كنتم تتسائلون
how I was doing, thank you for asking.
كيف كان حالي، أشكركم على سؤالكم.
It's Throwback Thursday already.
تلك صورة قديمة على أي حال.
I was involved in a heavy love affair
كنت متورط في حالة حب حادة
with the music of Duran Duran,
مع موسيقى دوران دوران،
as you can probably tell from my outfit.
يتضح ذلك تقريبًا من ملابسي.
I was in the middle.
أنا الذي في الوسط.
And the simplest way that I knew
وأبسط طريقة عرفتها
how to co-opt myself into that experience
لكيفية إدماج نفسي في تجربة الانتظار هذه
of wanting to be in that song somehow
لأكون في هذه الأغنية بطريقة أو أخرى
was to just get a band together of fellow nine-year-olds
كان مجرد تكوين فريق سويًا مع زملائي ذو التسع سنين
and play "Wild Boys" at the school talent show.
ونؤدي "أولاد أشقياء" في عرض المواهب بالمدرسة.
So that's what we did, and long story short,
لذلك هذا ما قمنا به، واختصارًا لقصة طويلة،
we were booed off the stage,
قابلونا بصيحات الاستهجان على المسرح،
and if you ever have a chance to live your life
ولوعندك فرصة واحدة لتعيش حياتك
escaping hearing the sound of an auditorium
تجاهل سماع الصوت القادم من صالة ممتلئة بالصف الثاني
full of second- and third-graders booing,
والثالث يصيحون باستهجان،
I would highly recommend it. It's not really fun.
أود أن أنصح به بشده.
But it didn't really matter,
لم تكن تهم فعلًا،
because what I wanted somehow
لأن ما أردته بطريقة أو أخرى كان مجرد أن أكون في تاريخ الأغنية لدقيقة.
I didn't care who liked it.
لا يعنيني من أعجبته.
I just loved it, and I thought I could put myself in there.
أحببتها فقط، و اعتقدت أن باستطاعتي وضع نفسي هناك.
Over the next 10 years, "La Di Da Di"
عبر العشر سنين التالية،
continues to be sampled by countless records,
أعيد دمج "لا دي دا دي" في تسجيلات لا حصر لها،
ending up on massive hits like "Here Comes the Hotstepper"
تنتهي إلى عدد ضخم من المشاهدات مثل "هنا يأتي الراقص الجذاب"
and "I Wanna Sex You Up."
و"أريد مضاجعتك".
Snoop Doggy Dogg covers this song
يضع سنوب دوجي دوج هذه الأغنية
on his debut album "Doggystyle" and calls it "Lodi Dodi."
في ألبومه الأول "دوجي ستايل" ويطلق عليها "لودي دودي"
Copyright lawyers are having a field day at this point.
وجد محامو حقوق الطباعة والنشر ضالتهم في تلك النقطة.
And then you fast forward to 1997,
ثم نتقدم سريعًا إلى 1997،
and the Notorious B.I.G., or Biggie,
يعيد بي أي جي سيئ السمعة، أو بيجي،
reinterprets "La Di Da Di"
إصدار "لا دي دا دي"
on his number one hit called "Hypnotize,"
في إصداره رقم واحد ويدعى "تنويمًا مغناطيسيًا"
which I will play a little bit of
الذي سوف أُشغل جزء بسيط منه
and I will play you a little bit of the Slick Rick
وسوف أُشغل جزء يسير من السليك ريك
to show you where they got it from.
لأُريكم من أين أتوا بها.
(Music: "Hypnotize" by The Notorious B.I.G.)
(موسيقى: "تنويم مغناطيسي" لبي أي جي سيء السمعة)
So Biggie was killed
ثم قتل بيجي
weeks before that song made it to number one,
قبل أسابيع من وصوله للقمة بهذه الأغنية،
in one of the great tragedies of the hip-hop era,
في واحدة من المآسي الكبرى في عصر الهيب هوب،
but he would have been 13 years old
لكنه كان في الثالثة من عمره تقريبًا
and very much alive when "La Di Da Di" first came out,
ومفعم بالحياة حين تم صدرت "لا دي دا دي" لأول مرة،
and as a young boy
وكطفل صغير
growing up in Brooklyn,
نشأ في بروكلين،
it's hard not to think that that song probably held
من الصعب عدم التفكير أن تلك الأغنية حملت
some fond memories for him.
بعض الذكريات الجميلة له.
But the way he interpreted it, as you hear,
لكن الطريقة التي أعاد بها الإصدار،
is completely his own.
كما سمعتم، تخصه تمامًا.
He flips it, makes it,
إنه يقلبها، ويصنعها،
there's nothing pastiche whatsoever about it.
لا توجد معارضة أدبية إطلاقًا حول هذا الموضوع.
It's thoroughly modern Biggie.
إنها بيجي حديثة تمامًا.
I had to make that joke in this room,
وجب على أن أُلقى هذه النكتة هنا،
because you would be the only people that I'd ever have a chance of getting it.
لأن أنتم الوحيدين الذين أمتلك الفرصة لقولها أمامهم.
And so, it's a groaner. (Laughter)
لذلك، هي نكتة سيئة. (ضحك)
Elsewhere in the pop and rap world,
في مكان آخر في عالم البوب والراب،
we're going a little bit sample-crazy.
في طريقنا لعينة جنون ضئيلة.
We're getting away from the obscure samples that we were doing,
نحن نبتعد عن العينات الغامضة التي نقوم بها،
and all of a sudden everyone's taking
وفجأة أخذ الجميع
these massive '80s tunes like Bowie, "Let's Dance,"
ألحان الثمانينيات الضخمة مثل بوي،"هيا نرقص،"
and all these disco records, and just rapping on them.
وكل تسجيلات الديسكو هذه وفقط يقرعون فوقها.
These records don't really age that well.
تلك تسجيلات لا تعيش طويلًا.
You don't hear them now, because they borrowed
أنتم لا تسمعوها الآن،
You can't just hijack nostalgia wholesale.
لا يمكنم حتى استعادة الشجن.
It leaves the listener feeling sickly.
إنها تترك المستمعين وهم متوعكون.
You have to take an element of those things
عليك أن تأخذ عنصر من تلك الأشياء
and then bring something fresh and new to it,
وتُحضر شيء حديث وناضر لها،
which was something that I learned
شيئ ما تعلمته
when I was working with the late,
حين كنت أعمل مع الراحلة،
amazing Amy Winehouse
الرائعة آمي واينهاوس
on her album "Back to Black."
في ألبومها "عودة للأسود."
A lot of fuss was made about the sonic of the album
أُثيرت ضجة كثيرة حول الصوتيات في الألبوم
that myself and Salaam Remi, the other producer,
التي أنجزتها أنا بنفسي وسلام ريمي،
achieved, how we captured this long-lost sound,
المنتج الآخر، كيف التقطتنا هذا الصوت
but without the very, very 21st-century personality
المفقود منذ زمن بعيد، لكن بدون شخصية القرن الحادي والعشرين
and firebrand that was Amy Winehouse
وزعيمة ذلك كانت آمي واينهاوس
and her lyrics about rehab and Roger Moore
وكلماتها عن ريهاب وروجر مور
and even a mention of Slick Rick,
وحتى ذكر سليك ريك،
the whole thing would have run the risk
أن تكون صادقًا،
of being very pastiche, to be honest.
هو الأمر برمته الذي قد يواجه خطر كونك في وضع معارضة أدبية.
Imagine any other singer from that era over it
تخيل أي مغني آخر من تلك الحقبة
singing the same old lyrics.
يغني نفس الكلمات القديمة.
It runs a risk of being completely bland.
أنه يواجه خطر كونك ممل تمامًا.
I mean, there was no doubt that Amy
أعني، كان لا يوجد شك أن آمي
and I and Salaam all had this love
وأنا وسلام جميعًا أمتلكنا هذا الحب
for this gospel, soul and blues and jazz
لإنجيل، وروح، وبلوز، وجاز
that was evident listening to the musical arrangements.
الذي كان واضحًا من الاستماع للترتيبات الموسيقية.
She brought the ingredients that made it urgent
أحضرت العوامل التي جعلتها ضرورية
and of the time.
ومعاصره.
So if we come all the way up to the present day now,
لذلك لو قطعنا طول الطريق حتى يومنا هذا،
the cultural tour de force that is Miley Cyrus,
التجربة التحديثية الكبرى كانت لميلي سايرس،
she reinterprets "La Di Da Di"
فهي تعيد إصدار "لا دي دا دي"
completely for her generation,
بالكامل لجيلها،
and we'll take a listen to the Slick Rick part
سوف نستمع إلى جزء لسليك ريك
and then see how she sort of flipped it.
ثم نرى كيف نظمته وقلبته.
(Music: "La Di Da Di" by Slick Rick &amp; Doug E. Fresh)
(موسيقى: "لا دي دا دي" لسليك ريك ودوج إي فريش)
(Music: "We Can't Stop" by Miley Cyrus)
(موسيقى: "لا نستطيع التوقف" لميلي سايرس)
So Miley Cyrus,
إذًا ميلي سايرس،
who wasn't even born yet when "La Di Da Di" was made,
التي حتى لم تكن ولدت حين تم إصدار "لا دي دا دي"
and neither were any of the co-writers on the song,
ولا أي مِن مَن شارك في كتابة الأغنية،
has found this song that somehow
قد وجدت هذه الأغنية التي بطريقة أو بأخرى
etched its way into the collective consciousness of pop music,
حفرت طريقها في الوعي الكلي لموسيقى البوب
and now, with its timeless playfulness of the original,
والآن، مع الاستمتاع الدائم بنسختها الأصلية،
has kind of translated to a whole new generation
امتلكت نوع من الترجمة للجيل الجديد بأكمله
who will probably co-opt it as their own.
الذي سوف يدمجها في الأغلب بطريقته.
Since the dawn of the sampling era,
منذ فجر حقبة إعادة الدمج،
there's been endless debate
هناك جدل لا نهائي
about the validity of music that contains samples.
حول شرعية الموسيقى التي تحتوي على أجزاء مدمجة.
You know, the Grammy committee says that
تعرفون، تقول لجنة الغرامي أنه
if your song contains some kind of pre-written
لو كانت أغنيتك تحتوي على موسيقى مكتوبة في السابق
or pre-existing music,
أو وجدت من قبل،
you're ineligible for song of the year.
تكون غير مؤهل للغناء لمدة عام.
Rockists, who are racist
عاشقو الروك، الذين هم متعصبون
but only about rock music,
فقط لموسيقى الروك،
constantly use the argument to —
يستخدمون باستمرار الحجة ل ـــ
That's a real word. That is a real word.
تلك كلمة صحيحة ، تلك كلمة صحيحة.
They constantly use the argument to devalue rap
باستمرار يستخدموا الحجة للتقليل من الراب
and modern pop,
والبوب الحديث،
and these arguments completely miss the point,
وتلك الحجج تفقد تمامًا الغاية،
because the dam has burst.
لأن السد قد انفجر.
We live in the post-sampling era.
نحن نعيش في عصر ما بعد إعادة الدمج.
We take the things that we love
نحن نأخذ الأشياء التي نحبها
and we build on them.
ونبني فوقها.
That's just how it goes.
هكذا فقط تسير الأمور.
And when we really add something significant and original
وحين نضيف حقًا شيء مميز وأصلي
and we merge our musical journey with this,
وندمج رحلتنا الموسيقية معه،
then we have a chance to be
حينها نمتلك فرصة لنكون
a part of the evolution of that music that we love
جزء من التطور لتلك الموسيقى التي نحبها
and be linked with it once it becomes something new again.
ونرتبط معها بمجرد أن تصبح شيئًا جديدًا مرةً أخرى.
So I would like to do one more piece
إذًا أود أن أشغل قطعة أخرى
that I put together for you tonight,
وضعتها سويًا من أجلكم الليلة،
and it takes place with two
ولهما مكان في أثنين
pretty inspiring TED performances that I've seen.
من أكثرعروض (تيد) الملهمة بشدة التي رأيتها .
One of them is the piano player Derek Paravicini,
واحدة منهما لعازف البيانو دريك بارفيتشيني،
who happens to be a blind,
الذي صادف أن يكون أعمى،
autistic genius at the piano,
عبقري متوحد على البيانو،
and Emmanuel Jal, who is an ex-child soldier
وإيمانويل جال، مجند طفل سابق
from the South Sudan,
من جنوب السودان،
who is a spoken word poet and rapper.
الذي هو شاعر الكلمة المنطوقة ومغني راب.
And once again I found a way to annoyingly
ومرة أخرى وجدت وسيلة لأدمج
me-me-me myself into the musical history
ن ن ن نفسي في التاريخ الموسيقي
of these songs,
لهذه الأغاني،
but I can't help it,
لكن لا يسعني ذلك،
because they're these things that I love,
لأنهم الأشياء التي أحبها،
and I want to mess around with them.
وأريد أن أتسكع معها.
So I hope you enjoy this. Here we go.
إذًا أتمنى أن تستمتعوا بهذه، سنبدأ.
Let's hear that TED sound again, right?
دعونا نستمع لصوت (تيد) مرة أخرى، متفقون؟
(Music)
(موسيقى)
Thank you very much. Thank you.
أشكركم جدًا، شكرًا لكم
(Applause)
(تصفيق)